Guide to the Yale Science and Engineering Association Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Science and Engineering Association records
1913-2003
RU 1089
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(5 boxes)
The material consists of meeting minutes, subject files and correspondence maintained by Hugo Beit (1953E), who served as secretary from 1963 to 2003.
Yale Science and Engineering Association
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 23-G (YRG 23-G), Records of School of Engineering alumni and support organizations.).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were a gift of Hugo Beit, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Engineering Association, an alumni organization, was founded in 1914 to encourage and recognize excellence and accomplishment in members of the Yale engineering community. In 1971 it expanded to include all the sciences, becoming the Yale Science and Engineering Association (YSEA).
Scope and Contents
The material consists of meeting minutes, subject files and correspondence maintained by Hugo Beit (1953E), who served as secretary from 1963 to 2003.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged chronologically.
Universities and colleges -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University. School of Engineering; Yale University -- Alumnae and alumnae -- Societies, etc.
- Yale Engineering Association Records, 1913-2003; Accession 2009-A-063
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Yale Scientific Magazine, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Summary of the first 25 years of YEA (Yale Engineering Association), circa 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History 1913-1956, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photos of Ken and Marjorie Lutz, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Publications, 1915-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, minutes, and other records, 1914-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6-14)
  - Organization charts and Executive Board directories, 1950-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence and other records, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, constitution and by-laws, treasurer's reports, yearly budget, etc., 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, minutes, and other records, 1952-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18-33)
  - Executive Board, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
  - Awards Committee, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, publicity, reports, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - President, James F. Thornton, records, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Minutes, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Board, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and publicity, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, minutes, and other records, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
  - Minutes, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - GRL (Gerard R. Lawrence) records, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - President, Alexander R. Cochran, records, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Awards Committee awards, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - President, Alexander R. Cochran, records, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2-9)
  - Minutes, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee, 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 12-15)
  - K-AYA file, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and other records, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
  - Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Schools committee, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, minutes, and other records, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 21-24)
  - Annual meeting, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and other records, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Minutes, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, minutes, and other records, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5-8)
  - Annual meeting, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and other records, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Annual meeting, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and other records, 1982-1983, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 12-20)
  - Correspondence, minutes, and other records, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1-8)
  - Correspondence and other records, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Annual meeting, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Correspondence, minutes, and other records, 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 13-17)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)